Sylvia Beach Papers, 1887-1966 (bulk 1920s-1950s ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Series 7: Photographs, 1881-1969; 14.1 linear feet 20 boxes
  - Subseries 7F: Photographs of Notable People, 1881-1968 June 11; 10.0 boxes (1 partial)
    - Wilde, Oscar, 1881-1893 May; 1.0 folder
      - Card Portrait: Oscar Wilde by Elliott & Fry, 1881; Elliott & Fry.; 1 item (Folder 6)
        Card mounted photograph from Elliott & Fry, 55 Baker Street, London. W.
      - Clipping of a Cartoon portrait: Titled "Oscar Wilde at Work (Il Ne Faut Pas Le Regarder)", undated; 6; portion of 1 folder (5.5 x 4 inches) (Folder 6)
        Captioned "Caricature of Oscar Wilde from an original drawing by Aubrey Beardsley"
      - Photographic Postcard: The Hôtel De La Plage, Titled "Berneval-Sur-Mer Près Dieppe (Seine-Inf.), Hôtel De La Plage", undated; 7; portion of 1 folder (3.5 x 5.5 inches) (Folder 6)
        inscribed "where Oscar Wilde stayed after he left prison"
    - Wilder, Thornton, 1936; 1.0 folder
      - Clipping of Formal portrait: Thornton Wilder, undated; 1; portion of 1 folder (on board 5.5 x 4.25 inches) (Folder 7)
      - Clipping of Formal portrait: Captioned "Thornton Wilder", undated; 2; portion of 1 folder (3.25 x 2.25 inches, on card 6.75 x 4.75 inches) (Folder 7)
      - Portrait: Thorton Wilder With Cigarette by Gisèle Freund, 1936; 1; 1 vintage stamped print and 2 copy prints portion of 1 folder (6 x 4.5 inches) (Folder 7)
        Written on reverse "Thornton Wilder, Writers’ Congress, Paris 1936," stamped on reverse "Please credit Gisèle Freund, 12, rue Lalande, Paris—XIVe"
    - Williams, William Carlos, 1924; 1.0 folder
      - Note Regarding Pictures of Children, undated; portion of 1 folder (Folder 8)
        Note states: "The pictures of the children (2 boys) in this folder are not of William Carlos Williams as a child, but of his two sons William Eric and Paul. They were taken the year they were in school in Switzerland. Florence Williams (their mother—Mrs. William Carlos Williams) was there with them. She is the woman in the three other small photos. Date: 1927-1928—Mary Ellen Solt"
      - Snapshots: William Carlos Williams With Wheelbarrow and Kittens in Rutherford, New Jersey, undated; 1; 2 copies portion of 1 folder (4.5 x 3.5 inches) (Folder 8)
        Captioned "Bill Williams in his garden in Rutherford, N.J.," inscribed on reverse "Sylvia Beach, 12 rue de l’Odéon"
      - Snapshot: William Carlos Williams Holding a Hoe in His Garden in Rutherford, New Jersey, undated; 2; portion of 1 folder (3.5 x 2.5 inches) (Folder 8)
        Captioned "Bill Williams in his garden, Rutherford, N.J.," inscribed on reverse "The rose garden and the fountain pen"
      - Snapshot: William Carlos Williams Kneeling in His Yard, undated; 3; portion of 1 folder (3.5 x 2.5 inches) (Folder 8)
        Captioned "Bill Williams," inscribed on reverse "a forehead like narcissi"
      - Snapshot: William Carlos Williams Sitting on a Stump With Kittens, undated; 4; portion of 1 folder (4.5 x 3.5 inches) (Folder 8)
        Captioned "Bill Williams ‘giving birth to 3 kittens,’" inscribed on reverse "Wm. Carlos Williams giving birth to 3 full grown kittens"
      - Snapshot: William Carlos Williams Sitting on a Stump, undated; 5; portion of 1 folder (3.5 x 2.5 inches) (Folder 8)
        Inscribed on reverse "peasant hands"
      - Snapshot: William Carlos Williams Standing on a Ship Deck, undated; 6; portion of 1 folder (2.5 x 1.75 inches) (Folder 8)
      - Snapshot: Florence Williams Standing on a Ship Deck, undated; 8; 3 images portion of 1 folder (2.5 x 1.75 inches) (Folder 8)
      - Snapshot: William Eric Williams Standing on a Ship Deck, undated; 10; 2 images portion of 1 folder (2.5 x 1.75 inches) (Folder 8)
      - Snapshot: Paul Williams Standing on a Ship Deck, undated; 12; portion of 1 folder (2.5 x 1.75 inches) (Folder 8)
      - Inscribed Formal Portrait: William Carlos Williams Looking Right by Man Ray, 1924; 14; Man Ray, 1890-1976; portion of 1 folder (11.25 x 9 inches (mounted on card 13 x 9.5 in frame 14.5 x 11.5)) (Folder 16)
        Inscribed "To Sylvia Beach—May 27-1924, Paris, William Carlos Williams," signed "Man Ray, Paris"
      - Copy Print: William Carlos Williams Looking Right by Man Ray, undated; 1; Man Ray, 1890-1976; 1 item (6.25 x 5 inches) (Folder 8)
    - Wilson, Edmund, 1931; 1; 1.0 folder (5.75 x 5 inches) (Folder 9)
      Removed from: Edmund Wilson, Axel’s Castle, NY 1931
    - Wolfe, Thomas, undated; 1.0 folder
      - Formal portrait: Thomas Wolfe With Arms Crossed, undated; 1; portion of 1 folder (10 x 8 inches, mounted on card 10.5 x 8.5 inches) (Folder 10)
      - Reproduction print: Thomas Wolfe in Profile, undated; 2; portion of 1 folder (9.25 x 7 inches, mounted on card 10.5 x 8.5 inches) (Folder 10)
    - Woolf, Virginia, undated; 1.0 folder
      See also: T.S. Eliot
      - Portrait: Virginia Woolf With Hand to Mouth, undated; 1 item (Folder 11)
      - Portrait: Virginia Woolf, undated; 1 item (Folder 11)
      - Clipping of Formal portrait: Virginia Woolf, undated; 3; portion of 1 folder (5 x 4 inches) (Folder 11)
      - Formal Portraits: Virginia Woolf by Gisèle Freund, undated; 1; 3 formal portraits mounted together (all 6 x 4 inches (mounted on card 8 x 15)) (Folder 11)
    - Wright, Richard, 1946; 1.0 folder
      - Inscribed Formal Portrait: Richard Wright by Max Yavno, 1946; 1; Yavno, Max; 1 vintage and 1 later copy print portion of 1 folder (9.75 x 7.5 inches) (Folder 12)
        Inscribed "To Sylvia Beach, Sincerely yours, Richard Wright, June 7, 1946, Paris," stamped on reverse "please credit photo by yavno"
      - Inscribed Formal Portrait: Richard Wright, 1946; 2; portion of 1 folder (9.5 x 8 inches) (Folder 12)
        Inscribed "To Sylvia Beach, Sincerely yours, Richard Wright, June 8, 1946, Paris," written on reverse "From: Frank Marshall Davis, 3507 South Parkway, Room 11, Chicago"
      - Snapshots: Wife Ellen Wright and Daughter Julia Wright, undated; 3; 4 images portion of 1 folder (2.75 x 4 inches) (Folder 12)
      - Formal Portrait: Richard Wright Holding an African Sculpture by Carl Van Vechten, undated; 16; Van Vechten, Carl, 1880-1964.; 1.0 folder (10 x 7.75 (mounted in frame 14.5 x 11.5) inches) (Folder 18)
        inscribed "To Sylvia Beach, Sincerely yours, Richard Wright, June 7, 1946, Paris"
    - Wylie, James H., undated; 1.0 folder
      - Portrait: James H. Wylie Looking at a Drawing of James Joyce Hanging on the Wall, undated; 1; 1.0 folder (5 x 3.5 inches) (Folder 13)
        Inscribed on reverse "Studying A Portrait of the Artist! JHW"
      - Negative (No Photo): James H. Wylie Formal Portrait With Hat, undated; 1.0 item (Folder 13)
    - Yeats, W.B., 1938; 1.0 folder
      - Photogravure: W.B. Yeats, undated; 1; portion of 1 folder (9 x 6.75 inches, mounted on card 10.5 x 7.75 inches) (Folder 14)
        "W.B. Yeats" signature printed on mount.
      - Clipping of Portrait: W. B. Yeats Sitting in a Chair Outside With Eyes Closed, 1938; 2; portion of 1 folder (7.25 x 7 inches, on card) (Folder 14)
        Captioned "W. B. Yeats, Menton, 1938, Photograph by kind permission of Miss Nora S. Herald"
  - Subseries 7G: Unidentified Photographs, 1923 December-1924 April; 1.0 box
    Contains unidentified photographs, 1923-1924, by known and unidentified photographers.
    This sub-series is currently unorganized.
    - Photographs: Unidentified Individuals by Boughton, Alice, 1923 December - 1924 April; Boughton, Alice, 1865-1943; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    - Unidentified Photographs, undated; 1.0 box (Folder 7)
    - Unidentified Negatives, undated; 1 folder (Folder 34)
  - Subseries 7H: Derivative Images and Notes, undated; 2 boxes (1 partial)
    The negatives included in this box were made by Sylvia Beach (likely in the early 1960s) of images in this collection. There are no unique images in this box. The originals are located throughout the rest of the series.
    No arrangement action was taken on this part of the collection during 2013 processing.
    - Card Catalogue of Photographs Created by Sylvia Beach, undated; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      Cards are arranged in alphabetical order and cards may contain further details about images.
    - Envelopes With Notes About Photographs, undated; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - Copy Negatives, undated; 1 box
      Copies of negative images arranged in alphabetical order with names on envelopes.
- Series 8: Memorabilia, 1953; 4 boxes (1 partial)
  The Memorabilia series contains objects acquired as part of the Sylvia Beach Papers. Of special interest are a set of tin soldiers with parade ground and the cabinet they were housed in at Shakespeare & Company, as well as various trinkets relating to William Shakespeare used to decorate the bookshop.
  Arranged by type of material.
  - Billfolds, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    In use at the time of Beach's death. Contains Sylvia Beach's driver's license, Legion of Honor documentation, and calling cards.
    Given by Holly Beach Dennis in April 1966.
  - Printing Plate for Calling Cards, undated; 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - Small Irish Flag and 2 Cards from Shakespeare & Company, undated; 1 folder (Folder 6)
  - Small Wooden Toy Theater Box, undated; 1 folder
  - Three Mounted Soldier Toys, undated; 1 folder
    These soldiers, representing George Washington and his staff, were housed in the small oak wall cabinet placed near the front of the bookstore to guard over the "House of Shakespeare."
    Donated by Valery Larbaud.
  - Seven Foot Soldier Toys, undated; 1 folder
  - Green Tray Which Served as the "Parade ground" for the Tin Soldiers, undated; 1 folder
  - Wooden Bust of Shakespeare, 1953; 1 folder
    The small round oak box is inscribed: "Oak from Shakespeare's Birth-Place" and Contains an inscription inside as well as a note from Sylvia's sister.
  - Impression of Shakespeare's Head in Red Wax from Seal, in Small Round Box, with Label of John Robertson, Seal Engraver, undated; 1 folder
  - Brass Door Knocker Representing Shakespeare, undated; 1 folder
  - Brass Door Knocker Representing Shakepeare's House at Stratford-on-Avon, undated; 1 folder
  - Brass Ash Tray with Shakepeare's Effigy, undated; 1 folder
  - China Replica of Shakepeare's House, undated; 1 folder
    Very fragile: please be careful with this item.
  - Bust of Shakespeare in Colored Staffordshireware, undated; 1 folder
    Staffordshireware figurine of William Shakespeare, n.d. Sylvia Beach received it as a gift from Lady Ellerman (the mother of Winifred Ellerman, better known as Bryher), who had purchased it in Brighton.
  - Cardboard Box with Label in Valéry Larbaud's Hand, undated; 1 folder
    Inscription reads: "West-Point at Shakespeare's birthplace. Together with a Greek flag-bearer for luck. With Major-General V. Larbaud's compliments."
  - Tin Box Painted with Railroad Scene, undated; 1 folder
  - Unidentified Wooden Box, undated; 1 folder
  - Small Oak Wall Cabinet, undated; 1 box
    The small oak wood cabinet contained a detachment of toy soldiers representing George Washington and his staff, supplied by Valery Larbaud to stand guard over the "House of Shakespeare." Beach hung the cabinet with the soldiers near the front door of Shakespeare & Company.
  - Oak Cabinet, undated; 1 item
  - Flameng, Leopold: Engraving of William Shakespeare, undated; portion of 1 box 31 x 23.5
    Includes small busts of David Garrick and Edwin Booth below. Formerly framed and hung in Shakespeare & Company.
- 32101037556550 (Box 1)
- 32101037556543 (Box 2)
- 32101037555610 (Box 3)
- 32101037555537 (Box 4)
- 32101037556790 (Box 5)
- 32101037555685 (Box 6)
- 32101037555701 (Box 7)
- 32101037555719 (Box 8)
- 32101037555545 (Box 9)
- 32101037555925 (Box 10)
- 32101037555552 (Box 11)
- 32101037555669 (Box 12)
- 32101037555867 (Box 13)
- 32101037556840 (Box 14)
- 32101037556733 (Box 15)
- 32101037556832 (Box 16)
- 32101037556816 (Box 17)
- 32101037556808 (Box 18)
- 32101037556634 (Box 19)
- 32101037556626 (Box 20)
- 32101037556618 (Box 21)
- 32101037556824 (Box 22)
- 32101037556527 (Box 23)
- 32101037556519 (Box 24)
- 32101037556501 (Box 25)
- 32101037556485 (Box 26)
- 32101037556956 (Box 27)
- 32101037555529 (Box 28)
- 32101037556923 (Box 29)
- 32101037556907 (Box 30)
- 32101037556915 (Box 31)
- 32101037556899 (Box 32)
- 32101037556881 (Box 33)
- 32101037555602 (Box 34)
- 32101037557178 (Box 35)
- 32101037557152 (Box 36)
- 32101037557145 (Box 37)
- 32101037557160 (Box 38)
- 32101037555677 (Box 39)
- 32101037555974 (Box 40)
- 32101037555982 (Box 41)
- 32101037555990 (Box 42)
- 32101037556261 (Box 43)
- 32101037556253 (Box 44)
- 32101037556311 (Box 45)
- 32101037556303 (Box 46)
- 32101037556329 (Box 47)
- 32101037556212 (Box 48)
- 32101037556428 (Box 49)
- 32101037557574 (Box 50)
- 32101037556220 (Box 51)
- 32101037556238 (Box 52)
- 32101037556295 (Box 53)
- 32101037556410 (Box 54)
- 32101037556246 (Box 55)
- 32101037556386 (Box 56)
- 32101037556030 (Box 57)
- 32101037556055 (Box 152)
- 32101037556998 (Box 153)
- 32101037556337 (Box 58)
- 32101037555966 (Box 59)
- 32101037556048 (Box 60)
- 32101037556006 (Box 61)
- 32101037556709 (Box 62)
- 32101037556683 (Box 63)
- 32101037556691 (Box 64)
- 32101037555578 (Box 65)
- 32101037556717 (Box 66)
- 32101037556725 (Box 67)
- 32101037555594 (Box 68)
- 32101037555586 (Box 69)
- 32101037556360 (Box 70)
- 32101037555560 (Box 71)
- 32101037556659 (Box 72)
- 32101037557558 (Box 73)
- 32101037557566 (Box 74)
- 32101037556667 (Box 75)
- 32101037556394 (Box 76)
- 32101037556378 (Box 77)
- 32101037556345 (Box 78)
- 32101037556980 (Box 154)
- 32101037555958 (Box 79)
- 32101037556451 (Box 80)
- 32101037556097 (Box 81)
- 32101037556121 (Box 82)
- 32101037556113 (Box 83)
- 32101037556105 (Box 84)
- 32101037556477 (Box 85)
- 32101037556584 (Box 86)
- 32101037556576 (Box 87)
- 32101037556469 (Box 88)
- 32101037556493 (Box 89)
- 32101037556436 (Box 90)
- 32101037556444 (Box 91)
- 32101037556568 (Box 92)
- 32101037555826 (Box 93)
- 32101037556758 (Box 94)
- 32101037555883 (Box 95)
- 32101037555891 (Box 96)
- 32101037555909 (Box 97)
- 32101037555917 (Box 98)
- 32101037557582 (Box 99)
- 32101037555818 (Box 100)
- 32101037555784 (Box 101)
- 32101037555792 (Box 102)
- 32101037555800 (Box 103)
- 32101037555743 (Box 104)
- 32101037555735 (Box 105)
- 32101037556782 (Box 106)
- 32101037555776 (Box 107)
- 32101037556204 (Box 108)
- 32101037555750 (Box 109)
- 32101037555768 (Box 110)
- 32101037555842 (Box 111)
- 32101037556865 (Box 112)
- 32101037556972 (Box 155)
- 32101037555834 (Box 113)
- 32101037556675 (Box 114)
- 32101037557590 (Box 115)
- 32101037556642 (Box 156)
- 32101037555727 (Box 157)
- 321010375556+3 (Box 116)
- 32101037557251 (Box 117)
- 32101037558564 (Box 118)
- 32101037558580 (Box 119)
- 32101037558572 (Box 120)
- 32101037558598 (Box 121)
- 32101037558606 (Box 122)
- 32101037556600 (Box 158)
- 32101037693080 (Box 159)
- 32101037557186 (Box 123)
- 32101037558614 (Box 124)
- 32101037556014 (Box 125)
- 32101037556022 (Box 126)
- 32101037556063 (Box 127)
- 32101037556071 (Box 128)
- 32101037556089 (Box 129)
- 32101037556279 (Box 130)
- 32101037556287 (Box 131)
- 32101037558622 (Box 132)
- 32101037556535 (Box 133)
- 32101037556196 (Box 134)
- 32101037556402 (Box 135)
- 32101037556154 (Box 136)
- 32101037556162 (Box 137)
- 32101037556170 (Box 138)
- 32101037556188 (Box 139)
- 32101037556147 (Box 140)
- 32101037556352 (Box 141)
- 32101037556949 (Box 142)
- 32101037556774 (Box 143)
- 32101037555644 (Box 144)
- 32101037555651 (Box 145)
- 32101037555636 (Box 146)
- 32101037557137 (Box 147)
- 32101037558648 (Box 148)
- 32101039273824 (Box 160)
- 32101039273972 (Box 177)
- 32101039273998 (Box 179)
- 32101039273816 (Box 161)
- 32101039274004 (Box 175)
- 32101039273964 (Box 172)
- 32101039273808 (Box 162)
- 32101039273790 (Box 163)
- 32101039273980 (Box 176)
- 32101039274012 (Box 174)
- 32101039273774 (Box 164)
- 32101039273782 (Box 165)
- 32101039274079 (Box 166)
- 32101039274061 (Box 167)
- 32101039273956 (Box 173)
- 32101039274053 (Box 168)
- 32101039274046 (Box 169)
- 32101039274038 (Box 170)
- 32101039274020 (Box 171)
- 32101039273766 (Box 178)
- 32101037558630 (Box 149)
- 32101037557004 (Box 150)
- 32101080516113 (Box 180)
- 32101037556964 (Box 151)
- 32101080848573 (Unitid 1)